Guide to the David Price Papers, 1960-2006 and undated RL.01048
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Congressional Papers Record Group, 1981-1994 and undated
  - Personal/Political Files Series, 1981-1994, bulk 1986-1994, 23 boxes
    - Correspondence Subseries, 1986-1994
      - 1989
        - Thank Yous (M.C.s [ Members of Congress] and Government), 1989 (Box CPP-15)
        - Thank Yous (Government and N.C. Groups), 1988-1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Thank Yous (National Groups), 1989 (Box CPP-15)
      - 1990
        - Personal Correspondence, 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Letters to Colleagues, 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Letters from Colleagues, 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Letters to Executive Agencies, 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Letters from Executive Agencies, 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Thank Yous (Individuals), 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Thank Yous (M.C.s) (Federal Government), 1990 (Box CPP-15)
        - Thank Yous (N.C. Groups), 1990 (Box CPP-16)
        - Thank Yous (National Groups), 1990 (Box CPP-16)
      - 1991
        - Personal Correspondence, 1991, 2 folders (Box CPP-16)
        - Letters to/from Colleagues, 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box CPP-16)
        - Letters to/from N.C. Government/Agencies, 1990-1991 (Box CPP-16)
        - Letters to/from Executive/National Agencies, 1991 (Box CPP-16)
        - Thank Yous (Individuals), 1991, 2 folders (Box CPP-16)
        - Thank Yous, Executive Agency (N.C. Groups), 1991-1992, 1 of 2 folders (Box CPP-16)
        - Thank Yous, Executive Agency (N.C. Groups), 1991-1992, 2nd of 2 folders (Box CPP-17)
        - Thank Yous (National Groups), 1991 (Box CPP-17)
      - 1992
        - DP Personal (In and Out), 1992 (Box CPP-17)
        - Personal Correspondence, 1992, 2 folders (Box CPP-17)
        - Letters to/from Miscellaneous VIPs, 1992 (Box CPP-17)
        - Letter to/from Colleagues, 1992 (Box CPP-17)
        - Letters to/from N.C. Government Agencies, 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box CPP-17)
        - Letters to/from Executive/National Agencies, 1992, 1 of 3 folders (Box CPP-17)
        - Letters to/from Executive/National Agencies, 1992, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box CPP-18)
        - Thank Yous-Individuals, 1992, 2 folders (Box CPP-18)
        - Thank Yous-N.C. Groups, Executive Agencies, 1991-1992 (Box CPP-18)
        - Thank Yous-National Groups, 1992 (Box CPP-18)
        - 1992 Congratulations-Individuals, 1992 (Box CPP-18)
        - Congratulations-National, 1992 (Box CPP-18)
      - 1993
        - Price Personal (In and Out), 1993 (Box CPP-18)
        - Personal Correspondence, 1993, 3 folders (Box CPP-18)
        - Letters to/from Colleagues, 1993 (Box CPP-19)
        - Letters to/from Non-Con. [Non-Constituent] VIPs, 1993 (Box CPP-19)
        - Letters to/from Local Officials, 1993 (Box CPP-19)
        - Letters to/from [N.C.] State Agencies, 1993, 2 folders (Box CPP-19)
        - Letters to/from Federal Agencies, 1993, 3 folders (Box CPP-19)
      - 1994
        - Personal Correspondence, 1994, 2 folders (Box CPP-19)
        - Price Personal (In and Out), 1994 (Box CPP-19)
        - Letters to/from Colleagues, 1994 (Box CPP-20)
        - Letters to/from Non-Con. [Non-Constituent] VIPs, 1993-1994 (Box CPP-20)
        - Letters to/from Local Officials, 1994, 2 folders (Box CPP-20)
        - Letters to/from State Agencies, 1994 (Box CPP-20)
        - Letters to/from Federal Agencies, 1994, 2 folders (Box CPP-20)
      - General Correspondence-Price (Personal) (87-90), 1987-1992 (In and Out) (Box CPP-20)
      - Price Personal (90-91), 1990-1993 (In and Out) (Box CPP-20)
      - Price Personal, 1988-1994 (In and Out) (Box CPP-20)
      - Recommendations, 1987-1994
        Contains a variety of documents but predominately is made up of recommendations by Price sent to various colleagues and branches of government. Often there is a written request, a written acknowledgement of the recommendation, résumés, and related documentation. Correspondents include White House official Bruce Lindsay of the Clinton Administration. These recommendations are for a range of positions, from placement in the freshman class at the University of North Carolina to ambassadorships and other top-level White House positions. The letters are arranged alphabetically by name of the person being recommended.
        - Allred, Amanda, 1990 (Box CPP-21)
        - Banik, Sambhu, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Barnes, Sarah Dillon, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Bergman, Ed, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Bowden, James, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Bradshaw, Joe, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Brodie, Keith, 1990-1991 (Box CPP-21)
        - Brower, David, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Brown, Katherine S., 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Brownlee, Mac, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Carter, Courtney Renee, 1991 (Box CPP-21)
        - Carter, Phil, 1988-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Castellaw, Christopher, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Chafe, Bill, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Chambers, JoAnne, 1989 (Box CPP-21)
        - Chou, Bill, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Colton, Marie, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Culberson, Jim, 1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Cutler, Lynn, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Davis, Lawrence, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Davis, Linda, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Dellinger, Walter, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Dixon, Ben F., 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Durham, Lynn, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Eisenbeis, Robert A., 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Farmer, Greg, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Farrell, Margaret, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Fordham, Chris, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Gallagher, Brian, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Garrison, William, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Gossman, Susan Carr, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Gwyther, Lisa, 1987 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hackney, Joe, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hagan, Katherine, 1992-1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hancock, Ellen, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hardaway, Thomas, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hart, Frank, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hawley, Willis, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hillman, Jennifer, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hoag, Mary Moore, 1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hogarth, William, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hubbard, Ann, 1989 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hunt, Betty Jo, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hunt, E.B., 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Hyde, Jeannette, 1993-1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Johnson, Ann, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Kahn, Thomas, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Kaufman, Wallace, 1992 (Box CPP-21)
        - Krakauer, Thomas H., 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Lapalombara, Joe, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Leach, Barbara, 1992-1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Leutze, James R., 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Lillie, David L., 1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Love, Judy, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Magnuson, Tom, 1994 (Box CPP-21)
        - Maier, Peter, 1993 (Box CPP-21)
        - Mills, Fetzer, 1992 (Box CPP-22)
        - Mills, Marshall, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Mottershead, Cheston V., 1992-1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Okun, Daniel, 1989 (Box CPP-22)
        - Perlmutter, Sandra, 1990-1991 (Box CPP-22)
        - Pigott, Brad, 1993-1994 (Box CPP-22)
        - Polsby, Nelson, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Price, Ernest L., 1993-1994 (Box CPP-22)
        - Reed, John Shelton, 1987 (Box CPP-22)
        - Rimer, Barbara, 1994 (Box CPP-22)
        - Ringland, Ann, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Robinson, Prezell, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Ruffin, John, 1989 (Box CPP-22)
        - Sandstrom, Karl, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Savage, Tobin, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Schmidt, Jonathan, 1994 (Box CPP-22)
        - Sebo, Paul G., 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Seymour, Frances, 1992-1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Smith, Ed, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Smith, A. Neal, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Speir, Betty, 1989 (Box CPP-22)
        - Stuart, Cathy, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Stutts, Ron, 1990 (Box CPP-22)
        - Vandergrift, Paul, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Weaver, Frank C., 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Welch, Ed, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Wells, Jeff, 1992-1994 (Box CPP-22)
        - Wells, Robin, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - White, James, 1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - White, Jesse L., 1990-1994 (Box CPP-22)
        - Winters, John W., 1990-1993 (Box CPP-22)
        - Wood, Melinda K., 1993 (Box CPP-22)
    - Campaign Files Subseries, 1983-1992 and undated
      Office files relating to Price's campaigns, with correspondence the most common document type. Most letters from North Carolina residents discuss a contribution, monetary or otherwise, to Price's campaign. There are some contact lists and a number of letters of congratulations after his primary and general campaigns in 1986. Folder topics include a North Carolina visit by Tom Foley, and the Democratic "Coordinated Campaign." Arranged alphabetically.
      - Congratulations Calls and Notes, 1986-1987, 1-3 of 4 folders (Box CPP-22)
      - Congratulations Calls and Notes, 1986-1987, 4 of 4 folders (Box CPP-23)
      - Coordinated Campaign (1992), 1992 (Box CPP-23)
      - Correspondence, 1985 July-1986 May, 2 folders (Box CPP-23)
      - Correspondence, 1986, 2 folders (Box CPP-23)
      - Correspondence, Pending, 1985-1986 (Box CPP-23)
      - Counties
        - Chatham County, undated (Box CPP-23)
        - Franklin County, 1985 (Box CPP-23)
        - Orange County, 1985-1986 (Box CPP-23)
        - Outside District, 1985 and undated (Box CPP-23)
        - Randolph County, 1983-1985 and undated (Box CPP-23)
        - Wake County, 1985-1986 and undated (Box CPP-23)
      - David Price, 1985 and undated (Box CPP-23)
      - Democratic National Convention, 1988 (Box CPP-23)
      - Tom Foley Visit (9/11), 1987 (Box CPP-23)
  - Legislative Files Series, 1981-1994, bulk 1987-1994 and undated, 66 boxes
    Correspondence, clippings, published materials, office files, memos, Congressional Research Service documents, targeted mailings, newsletters from a variety of organizations, notes, committee testimony, and speeches, all documenting Price's participation in the introduction and movement of bills, his general legislative interests, impact, and influence, as well as the interaction of legislative concerns and interests with the pressures of his constituency. It is unclear whether this was a central file in Price's office, whether it belonged to Price or another staff member, or whether it was shared by several staffers who worked on legislative initiatives and policy decisions with Price.
    The most common correspondents are Price, other members of Congress, and Senators involved in the legislative initiative, especially those serving on a relevant committee. Letters from constituents and constituent organizations on particular issues are often found in these files, as are Price's responses. Another significant document type frequently found in these files is the briefing memo, sent between staff members of Price's office, which serve as direct evidence of how Price's staff worked together on issues, communicated their expertise to him, and developed policy positions and legislative initiatives.
    Most files are arranged in subseries according to House committee areas of jurisdiction. Within most subseries, the files are not arranged in any particular order. Committee and subcommittee structures and their names changed over time, and very often one committee's jurisdiction will overlap another's. Familiarity with committee jurisdictions of the late 1980s and 1990s will be helpful in searching these files.
    See also correspondence found within the Personal/Political Files of the Congressional Papers.
    - Agriculture Subseries, 1987-1994
      Relates to various agricultural projects and legislative initiatives. Among the prominent correspondents are RJR Nabisco, Philip Morris, other tobacco industry interest groups, the Department of Agriculture (especially Secretary Mike Espy), and North Carolina State University. Frequent topics include an ASCS (Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service) awards program and various tobacco industry issues (taxing, pricing, nicotine spiking).
      See also Congressional Papers-Legislative Files-Appropriations-Agriculture.
      - AG-Tobacco, 1991-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-1)
      - ASCS [Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service] Awards Ceremony, 1991-1993 (Box CLE-1)
      - AG-Miscellaneous-Replies to DP, 1987-1993 (Box CLE-1)
    - Appropriations Subseries, 1985-1994 and undated
      Concerns government appropriations initiatives and related programs. There are many copies of outgoing letters that were sent to committee members asking for appropriations or support for a particular appropriations bill important to North Carolina. Letters between Congresspersons often discuss or request specific language be included in a bill. Drafts of letters from Price to constituents are also common.
      Document types are diverse and include the following: committee and conference reports; printed materials, especially informational documents such as fact sheets and documents that were likely kept as background/support materials; memos; bills; hearing documents; and correspondence, especially Dear Colleague letters.
      The files are in order roughly by legislative subject area. Within each one, the files are unarranged. Since the subcommittees changed names and jurisdictions over time, search in multiple categories for a comprehensive search.
      - Agriculture, 1990-1994
        Relates to various agricultural projects or legislative initiatives requiring funding. Correspondents include Appropriations committee members, especially Richard J. Durbin, and officials from the U.S. Department of Agriculture and North Carolina State University. Letters very often ask for support for a particular project. Topics mentioned include Appropriations Committee selection, and agriculture-related projects especially in North Carolina. Projects range from FDA drug approvals to the Bowman Gray Nutrition Center in Winston-Salem, N.C. There is no clear difference between many of these files and the Agriculture files immediately preceding the Appropriations Subseries.
        - AG-App FY [Fiscal Year] '95, 1994(2 folders), 2 folders (Box CLE-1)
        - Appropriations Subcommittee Selection, 103rd Congress, 1991-1992 (Box CLE-1)
        - AG-FY '95 Projects, 1994 (Box CLE-1)
        - AG-App Projects FY '94, 1992-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-1)
        - AG-App FY '94, 1993, 2 folders (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-App FY '93, 1992, 2 folders (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-App '93 Requests, 1991-1993 (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-App FY '92, 1991, 2 folders (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-App Projects FY '92, 1991-1992 (Box CLE-2)
        - AG- Hearings '91, 1991 (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-Hearings '92, 1992 and undated (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-Bowman-Gray, 1990-1994 (Box CLE-2)
        - AG-App N.C., Unrequested Items (Box CLE-2)
      - Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary (CJS) Subseries, 1985-1994
        Concerns matters of commerce, justice, state and the judiciary, and related appropriations legislation and initiatives. There are a variety of office documents, including David Price's 1989 testimony before the Appropriations-CJS Subcommittee. Correspondents include the North Carolina Biotechnology Center, Appropriations Committee members, and the National Textile Center. Organizations mentioned often include: the Southeast Consortium on Severe Thunderstorms and Tornadoes; (TC)2 (Textile/Clothing Technology Corporation); and a variety of other projects requiring funding, such as the National Coastal Resources Research and Development Institute (NCRI), TV Marti, storm research, and the National Endowment for Democracy.
        - Commerce Appropriations, FY '89, 1987-1989 (Box CLE-3)
        - CJS Conference Amendments, 1994 (Box CLE-3)
        - CJS Projects-FY '95, 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-3)
        - CJS App-FY '95, 1994, 3 folders (Box CLE-3)
        - CJS Projects-FY '94, 1993-1994 (Box CLE-3)
        - CJS App-FY '94, 1993, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box CLE-3)
        - CJS App-FY '94, 1993, 3 of 3 folders (Box CLE-4)
        - Commerce Appropriations, FY '92, 1991 (Box CLE-4)
        - Commerce-SE [Southeast] Storm Research, 1989-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-4)
        - Commerce-TC2 [Textile/Clothing Technology Corporation], 1985-1991 (Box CLE-4)
        - Commerce-Textile Center, 1990-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-4)
      - Defense, 1991-1994
        Concerns matters of defense appropriations and related legislation and initiatives. There are multiple Appropriations Committee Reports accompanying Defense Appropriations bills. Correspondents include North Carolina State University; Duke University; the University of North Carolina; and the Arms Control and Foreign Policy Caucus, which distributed Special Alerts on defense-related issues. Other prominent topics include textiles for military use, and various defense appropriations bills. See also Military Construction within the Appropriations Series.
        - Defense Projects, 1991-1994 (Box CLE-4)
        - Defense Appropriations, FY '95, 1994 (Box CLE-4)
        - Defense Appropriations, FY '94, 1993, 3 folders (Box CLE-5)
        - Defense Appropriations, FY '93, 1992-1993, 3 folders (Box CLE-5)
        - Defense Appropriations, FY '92, 1991 (Box CLE-5)
        - Military Construction App-FY '92, 1991 (Box CLE-5)
      - District of Columbia, 1992-1994
        Relates to Appropriations Bills specifically for the District of Columbia and include a conference report and appropriation bill. Correspondents include other House Members and DC mayor Sharon Pratt.
        - DC Appropriations Act, FY '95, 1994 (Box CLE-5)
        - DC Appropriations, FY '94, 1993 (Box CLE-5)
        - DC Appropriations, FY '93, 1992 (Box CLE-5)
      - Energy and Water, 1991-1994 and undated
        Correspondents in these files frequently include officials in various North Carolina organizations (e.g. ports authority and state government). Topics include Falls Lake, Jordan Lake, and the Forest Ridge Peninsula Park. See also Congressional Files/Legislative Files/Appropriations/Rural Development.
        - Energy and Water Appropriations, FY '95, 1994 (Box CLE-6)
        - Energy/Water Projects, 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box CLE-6)
        - Energy/Water App Projects, FY '93, 1991-1992 (Box CLE-6)
        - Energy/Water-Falls Lake, 1991-1992 (Box CLE-6)
        - Energy/Water-Falls Lake, 1988 (Box CLE-6)
        - Energy/Water-Falls Lake, 1992 (Box CLE-6)
        - Falls Lake, 1986-1992 (Box CLE-6)
        - Forest Ridge Peninsula Park, 1982-1993, 2 folders (Box CLE-6)
        - Forest Ridge Peninsula Park, 1982-1993 (Map-case OC:VII:2)
        - Jordan Lake, 1991 and undated (Box CLE-6)
      - Foreign Operations, 1990-1994 and undated
        Concerns foreign affairs and related appropriations legislation and initiatives. Prominent correspondents include North Carolina State University; the Sierra Club; David R. Obey (chair of the Foreign Operations Appropriations Subcommittee); and the University of North Carolina's Kenan Institute. Topics frequently mentioned include foreign operations appropriations, the Kenan Institute of Private Enterprise (MBA Enterprise Corps), Thailand development partnership with the United States, and collaborative research with Russia.
        - Collaborative Research Support Programs (CRSPs), 1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - Foreign Operations Appropriations FY '94, 1993 (Box CLE-7)
        - Kenan Institute, 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-7)
        - North Carolina Global TransPark, 1993-1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - NCSU [North Carolina State University]/Russian Project, 1992 (Box CLE-7)
        - Foreign Operations, FY '95, 1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - Foreign Operations, FY '93, 1992 (Box CLE-7)
        - Foreign Operations: International Medicine, FY '93, undated (Box CLE-7)
        - Foreign Operations: MBA Enterprise Corps, 1990-1993 (Box CLE-7)
      - Interior, 1989-1994
        Topics mentioned in this group of files include the HBCU [Historically Black Colleges and Universities] Historic Preservation Initiative and Shaw University's Leonard Hall. Correspondents include the North Carolina Department of Cultural Resources; Sidney R. Yates (Illinois Congressman who served on the House Appropriations Subcommittee on Interior and Related Agencies); and the U.S. Department of the Interior.
        - Interior Appropriations, FY '90, 1989 (Box CLE-7)
        - Mason House, Jordan Lake, 1981-1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - Leonard Hall, 1992-1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - Interior Appropriations Bill, FY '95, 1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - Interior Appropriations, FY '94, 1993-1994 (Box CLE-7)
        - Interior Projects, 1991-1992, 1 of 2 folders (Box CLE-7)
        - Interior Projects, 1991-1992, 2 of 2 folders (Box CLE-8)
      - Labor, Health, and Human Services (Labor-HHS) and Education, 1987-1993
        Correspondents in this group of files include William Natcher (chair of the Appropriations Subcommittee on Labor-HHS and Education) and APSA [American Political Science Association]. Prominent topics and projects seeking appropriations include: Shaw University's Estey Hall; NIEHS [National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences] facilities in RTP [Research Triangle Park], N.C.; the Congressional Fellowship Program; the HBCU Capital Financing Program; and literacy resource centers. Price's testimony to the Appropriations Subcommittee is included. See also Congressional Files/Legislative Files/Appropriations/VA-HUD for additional files on education-related appropriations.
        - Labor-HHS (Box CLE-8)
          - FY '95 Projects, 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box CLE-8)
          - FY '92-Education Programs, 1991 (Box CLE-8)
          - FY '94 Projects, 1993 (Box CLE-8)
          - FY '93 Projects, 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box CLE-8)
        - Education Request, FY '94, 1993 and undated (Box CLE-8)
        - Appropriations-APSA [American Political Science Association], 1990 (Box CLE-8)
        - App-Labor-HHS-NIEHS [National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences], 1987-1989 (Box CLE-8)
        - NSF [National Science Foundation]: Budget Questions, 1990 (Box CLE-8)
        - Labor-HHS Appropriations, FY '90, 1989 (Box CLE-8)
        - Estey Hall, Labor-HHS Appropriations, 1987 (Box CLE-8)
      - Legislative Branch, 1989
        Materials relate to the legislative branch of government and associated appropriations. One letter from another Member of Congress to Price thanks him for supporting a particular amendment.
        - Legislative Branch Appropriations, FY '90, 1989 (Box CLE-8)
      - Military Construction, 1989
        Relates to military construction and related appropriations legislation and initiatives. One letter is from Dick Armey discussing a particular vote. Prominent topics include base closings.
        - Military Construction, FY '90, 1989 (Box CLE-8)
      - Rural Development, 1989
        Prominent topics in these files include the North Carolina Biotechnology Center. Also here is a 1989 statement by David Price to the Rural Development Appropriations Subcommittee (before his membership).
        - Rural Development Appropriation FY '90, 1989 (Box CLE-8)
      - Transportation, 1987-1994 and undated